A Guide to the Papers of the United States House of Representatives Committee on Internal Security, 1971-1974
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the United States House of Representatives Committee on Internal Security 1971-1974
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11406
Collection contains 37,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Stored off-site. Users must request boxes 48 hours in advance of desired use. Neither drop-in nor next-day requests can be fulfilled. For additional information, contact Special Collections.
Acquisition Information
Collection was a gift from Clifford A. Kiracofe, Jr., Free Union, Va., 08 June 1998.
Scope and Content Information
Papers of the United States House of Representatives Committee on Internal Security, consisting primarily of office correspondence, intelligence reports, memoranda, and printed materials. Among the collected printed ephemera are publications such as People's Yellow Pages of America, The Call Political Newspapers of the October League, and The Daily World. There are also files on alleged radical organizations, such as: Operation Push, Communist Party, USA, the Sparticist League, and the Harrisburg 8. Also included are card files, House Committee manuals on Internal Security, and miscellaneous Department files.
Contents List
- Ad Hoc Committee of Concerned Citizens 1971 (Box 1)
- All African Peoples' Revolutionary Party 1972-1973 (Box 1)
- Alliance to End Repression 1965-1974 (Box 1)
- Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America 1974 (Box 1)
- American Civil Liberties Union 1973-1974 (Box 1)
- American Friends Service Committee 1972-1974 (Box 1)
- American Indian Movement 1973-1974 (Box 1)
- American Servicemen's Union 1973-1974 (Box 1)
- Amnesty International 1974 (Box 1)
- Anarchist 1971 (Box 1)
- Stanton Anderson 1974 (Box 1)
- Angela Davis Defense Committee 1971-1972 (Box 1)
- Annual Report—1972 Minority 1972 (Box 1)
  2 folders
- Anti-Draft Activities 1971 (Box 1)
- Anti-Fascist Commentator 1973-1974 (Box 1)
- Antonio Gramsci Conference 1973 (Box 1)
- John M. Ashbrook 1971 (Box 1)
- Attica Brigade 1974 (Box 1)
- Attica Prison Revolt 1970-1974 (Box 1)
- Black Liberation Army 1973-1974 (Box 1)
- Black Militant 1973 (Box 1)
- Black Muslims 1972-1973 (Box 1)
- Black P Stone Nation 1971-1972 (Box 1)
- Black Panther Report 1971 (Box 1)
  3 folders
- Black September Group 1972-1973 (Box 1)
- Bolling, Hansen, and Martin—Debates on the Floor 1973-1974 (Box 1)
- Bomb Demonstration (Letter and Book) 1973 (Box 1)
- Bombings 1972 (Box 1)
- Brown Berets Organization 1971 (Box 1)
- Buell, Edgar M. (Witnesses) 1972 (Box 1)
- C 1971-1975 (Box 1)
- California Israeli Committee For Trade and Technology 1972 (Box 1)
- Camp News 1972 (Box 1)
- Canadian Coalition of War Resistors 1973 (Box 1)
- Catholic Worker 1972-1974 (Box 1)
- Center for Marxist Education 1973 (Box 1)
- Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors 1970 (Box 1)
- Chicago 1972 (Box 1)
- Chicago Activists 1972 (Box 1)
- Chicago Area Draft Resistors 1974 (Box 1)
- Chicago Area Group on Latin America 1973-1974 (Box 1)
- Chicago Area Military Project (Camp) 1973 (Box 1)
- Chicago Citizens' Committee to Save Lives in Chile (CCSLC) 1974 (Box 1)
- Chicago Committee for American-Soviet Friendship 1971-1973 (Box 1)
- Chicago Committee for the Liberation of Angola, Mozambique, and Guine 1973 (Box 1)
- Chicago Connections 1973-1974 (Box 1)
- Chicago Peace Action Coalition 1971-1974 (Box 1)
- Chicago Peace Council 1971-1972 (Box 1)
- Chicago Peace Council 1973 (Box 1)
- Chicago Peace Council 1974 (Box 1)
- Chicago Seed 1972-1973 (Box 1)
- Chicago 7 1972-1973 (Box 1)
- Chicago Student Health Project 1974 (Box 1)
- Chicago Vets for Peace 1972 (Box 1)
- Chicago Women for Peace 1972 (Box 1)
- China 1971-1974 (Box 1)
- China Books and Periodicals 1974 (Box 1)
- Church League of America 1974 (Box 1)
- Citizens Committee on the Energy Crisis 1974 (Box 1)
- Citywide Coalition for Community Control of Police, Chicago 1972 (Box 1)
- Clark, Ramsey 1972-1973 (Box 2)
- Class Struggle League 1973-1974 (Box 2)
- Coalition for Jobs and Economic Justice 1973 (Box 2)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) 1974 (Box 2)
- Colleges 1971 (Box 2)
- Columbus Hearings 1973 (Box 2)
- Committee for Action/Research on the Intelligence Community 1973 (Box 2)
- Committee of Responsibility 1974 (Box 2)
- Resolutions and Agenda Committee on Internal Security 1973 (Box 2)
- Committee for Solidarity with the Korean People 1974 (Box 2)
- Committee of Liaison with Families of Servicemen 1972 (Box 2)
- Committee Meetings 1971 (Box 2)
- Committee Meetings 1972 (Box 2)
- Committee Meetings 1973 (Box 2)
- Committee Meetings 1974 (Box 2)
- Committee Meetings—Executive Agenda of Meetings 1972 (Box 2)
- Committee to Defend Carlos Feliciano 1974 (Box 2)
- Committee to Defend the Panthers 1970 (Box 2)
- Committee to Support Middle East Liberation 1973 (Box 2)
- Communist League 1973-1974 (Box 2)
- Communist Party, USA 1971-1974 (Box 2)
- Communist Party, USA—Party Affairs 1972 (Box 2)
- Communist Party—Illinois 1971-1974 (Box 2)
- Communist Party—Indiana 1974 (Box 2)
- Communist Party—Mexico 1974 (Box 2)
- Communist Party—New York 1973 (Box 2)
- Communist Party—Wisconsin 1974 (Box 2)
- Conference on the Military in American Society 1972 (Box 2)
- Congressional Record Inserts Ashbrook Jan-Jun 1972 (Box 2)
- Conspiracy 7 1972-1974 (Box 2)
- Contempt Cases 1972-1974 (Box 2)
- COPE 1971 (Box 2)
- Corporate Intelligence Alliance 1973 (Box 2)
- Cuba 1973-1974 (Box 2)
- Czechoslovakia 1974 (Box 2)
- Daily World 1971 (Box 2)
- De Mau Mau 1972-1973 (Box 2)
- Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee 1974 (Box 2)
- Demonstrations (April 24ߝMay 5) 1971 (Box 2)
- Deserters 1972 (Box 2)
- D.C. Coalition for Peace and Justice 1971 (Box 2)
- East Germany 1973 (Box 3)
- Ellisberg, Daniel 1971 (Box 3)
- Emergency Detention Act 1971 (Box 3)
- Eqbal Ahmad 1973 (Box 3)
- European Marxists 1973 (Box 3)
- The Extremist Speaks 1971 (Box 3)
- Federal Loyalty and Security Subcommittee—Preyer, Chr., Pepper, Ashbrook, and Zion 1973-1974 (Box 3)
- Forrester, Al 1971 (Box 3)
- Foundation for Change Inc. 1973 (Box 3)
- Four of Us (Box 3)
- Fourth International 1974 (Box 3)
- The Front Line 1974 (Box 3)
- G 1971-1975 (Box 3)
- Georgia Power —J. Wyman Lamb 1973-1974 (Box 3)
- Glide Memorial Church 1971 (Box 3)
- Golash, Mike 1971 (Box 3)
- Guardian 1973-1974 (Box 3)
- Guns 1973-1974 (Box 3)
- Hall, Gordon 1971 (Box 3)
- Harrisburg 8 1972 (Box 3)
- Hassan, Colonel 1971 (Box 3)
- High Point (N.C.) Police Department 1971 (Box 3)
- Hijacking 1972 (Box 3)
- Horner, Robert M., Staff Director 1973-1974 (Box 3)
- Hoover, J. Edgar, FBI Director 1971 (Box 3)
- House Committee on Internal Security 1973 Appropriation 1973 (Box 3)
- House Committee on Internal Security 1973 Appropriation 1974 (Box 3)
- Hungary 1974 (Box 3)
- Indians—Federal Building, Washington, D.C. 1972-1973 (Box 3)
- Indochina Bulletin 1973 (Box 3)
- Indochina Peace Campaign 1974 (Box 3)
- Industrial Workers of the World 1971-1973 (Box 3)
- Institute for Policy Studies (IPS) 1973 (Box 3)
- Internal Security, Committee on 1974 (Box 3)
- Internal Security Minority Report Major Coalitions in America's Antiwar Movement: 1965-1972 1972 (Box 3)
- Internal Security Report 1973 (Box 3)
- Internal Security, Staff Meetings Committee on 1973 (Box 3)
- Internal Security: Clippings, Tear Sheets From the Record Supporting the Committee 1974 (Box 3)
- Internal Security: Former Prisoners of War in Vietnam 1973 (Box 3)
- Internal Security: Letters Supporting the Committee 1971-1974 (Box 3)
- Internal Security: Prisoners of War 1971-1973 (Box 3)
- International Association of Chiefs of Police 1971-1974 (Box 3)
- International Internal Discussion Bulletin 1973-1974 (Box 3)
- International Arts and Sciences Press 1971 (Box 3)
- International Socialists 1973-1974 (Box 3)
- Iranian Students Association in the United States 1973 (Box 3)
- Ireland 1974 (Box 3)
- Irish Republican Army 1973-1974 (Box 3)
- Kent State 1970-1973 (Box 3)
- Ku Klux Klan 1974 (Box 3)
- Labor Today 1974 (Box 3)
- Labor Unions 1974 (Box 3)
- Lane, Gary 1972-1974 (Box 3)
- Latin American Defense Organization 1971-1973 (Box 3)
- Lawyers Committee on American Policy Toward Vietnam 1969 (Box 3)
- Liberation 1972-1973 (Box 3)
- Living Theatre 1971 (Box 3)
- Marxist-Leninist Collectives 1971
- Massachusetts State Police 1970-1971 (Box 3)
- Medical Aid for Indochina, Inc. 1973 (Box 3)
- Medical Education in Red China 1973 (Box 3)
- Medical Committee for Human Rights 1971-1974 (Box 3)
- Memorandums from the Majority 1972 (Box 3)
- Memorandums to Majority Staff 1972 (Box 3)
- Metcalf Report on Misuse of Police Authority 1973 (Box 3)
- Miami Hearings 1972 (Box 4)
- Middle East Research and Information Project 1974 (Box 4)
- Midwest Academy 1973 (Box 4)
- The Militant 1973-1974 (Box 4)
- Militant Labor Forum 1972 (Box 4)
- Minority Staffing 1971 (Box 4)
- Minority Witnesses 1972 (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous Organizations 1971 (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous Organizations: Washington, D.C. 1971 (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous Personalities 1973 (Box 4)
- Movement for a Democratic Military 1972 (Box 4)
- Murupa, Miguel (Dr.) 1971 (Box 4)
- Nameless Groups 1973-1974 (Box 4)
- National Caucus of Labor Committees 1973-1974 (Box 4)
- National Coalition for Fair Immigration Laws and Practices 1974 (Box 4)
- National Committee against Repressive Legislation 1974 (Box 4)
- National Committee for the Restoration of Civil Liberties in the Philippines 1974 (Box 4)
- National Conference of Puerto Rican Women, Inc. 1973 (Box 4)
- National Committee on United States China Relations, Inc. 1969 (Box 4)
- National Coordinating Committee for Trade Union Action and Democracy 1972-1974 (Box 4)
- National Council of Churches 1973-1974 (Box 4)
- National Defense Organization Against Racist and Political Repression 1971-1975 (Box 4)
- National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee 1971-1973 (Box 4)
- National Information Center 1971 (Box 4)
- National Lawyers Guild, Chicago Chapter 1973-1974 (Box 4)
- National League of Families of American Prisoners and Missing in Southwest Asia 1972 (Box 4)
- National Organization for Women 1973 (Box 4)
- National Peace Action Coalition 1971-1973 (Box 4)
- National Socialist White People's Party (NSWPP) 1973-1974 (Box 4)
- National States Rights Party 1973 (Box 4)
- National Student Association 1971 (Box 4)
- National United Committee to Free Angela Davis and All Political Prisoners 1971 (Box 4)
- Native American Movement 1974 (Box 4)
- New American Movement 1973 (Box 4)
- New Left Notes 1973 (Box 4)
- New Mobilization Committee to End the War in Vietnam Report 1971 (Box 4)
- New Politics 1973 (Box 4)
- New University Conference 1972 (Box 4)
- New University Thought 1974 (Box 4)
- New World Resource Center 1973-1974 (Box 4)
- North Korea 1973 (Box 4)
- October League 1973-1974 (Box 4)
- Operation Push 1971-1974 (Box 4)
- Operation Zebra 1974 (Box 4)
- Otero, Raphael 1973-1974 (Box 4)
- Pacific Research and World Empire Telegram 1973 (Box 4)
- Pacifica Foundation 1971 (Box 4)
- Pacifist Groups 1974 (Box 4)
- Peace Action Coalition—Washington Area 1971 (Box 4)
- Peace Action Council—Los Angeles 1973 (Box 4)
- Peace and Freedom Party 1971 (Box 4)
- Peace and World Affairs Center 1971 (Box 4)
- Peace Fronts Miscellaneous 1971-1974 (Box 4)
- Peoples Coalition for Peace and Justice 1971 (Box 5)
- Peoples Coalition for Peace and Justice (Chicago) 1972 (Box 5)
- People's Party 1971-1973 (Box 5)
- People's Platform 1971 (Box 5)
- People's Republic of China 1974 (Box 5)
- People's Yellow Pages of America 1974 (Box 5)
- Pentagon Papers 1971 (Box 5)
- Press 1971 (Box 5)
- Prisons 1971-1973 (Box 5)
- Prisoners Solidarity Committee (PSC) 1974 (Box 5)
- Progressive, The 1972 (Box 5)
- Progressive Labor—Students for a Democratic Society 1973 (Box 5)
- People's Bicentennial Commission 1974 (Box 5)
- Progressive Labor Party 1971 (Box 5)
- Puerto Rican Groups 1973 (Box 5)
- Puerto Rican Solidarity Committee 1974 (Box 5)
- A Quaker Action Group 1970 (Box 5)
- Quantum 1973 (Box 5)
- Racist Miscellaneous 1971 (Box 5)
- Radical Education Project 1971 (Box 5)
- Radical Political Economics 1972 (Box 5)
- Radio Free People 1971 (Box 5)
- Raids-Drugs 1973 (Box 5)
- Rally for Jobs and Justice, Chicago 1973 (Box 5)
- Raza Unida Party of Illinois 1973 (Box 5)
- Red China 1973-1974 (Box 5)
- Reiss, Richard (Detective) 1971 (Box 5)
- Resolutions Committee 1973 (Box 5)
- Revolutionaries 1971 (Box 5)
- Revolutionary Communist Youth 1973-1974 (Box 5)
- Revolutionary Socialist League 1974 (Box 5)
- Revolutionary Student Brigade (RSG) formerly Attica Brigade 1974 (Box 5)
- Revolutionary Union 1971-1974 (Box 5)
- Reorganization Bill (Establishing the Minority Staff) 1971 (Box 5)
- Rising Up Angry 1972-1974 (Box 5)
- Rutherford Defense Fund 1971 (Box 5)
- Safe Return 1973 (Box 5)
- Sanchez, Ferdinand E. 1972 (Box 5)
- Sanders, Donald G. 1971-1973 (Box 5)
- Science for the People 1973 (Box 5)
- Scientists and Engineers for Social and Political Action 1974 (Box 5)
- Second City 1972-1974 (Box 5)
- The Seed 1973 (Box 5)
- Shifrin, Avraham Minority Witness 1973 (Box 5)
- Skolnick, Sherman H. 1973 (Box 5)
- Socialist Labor Party 1974 (Box 5)
- Socialist Workers Party 1971-1974 (Box 5)
- Socialist Workers Party—Chicago 1974 (Box 5)
- Soledad Brothers Legal Committee 1972 (Box 5)
- Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr I. 1974 (Box 5)
- South America 1973 (Box 5)
- South Vietnam 1974 (Box 5)
- Southern Christian Leadership Conference 1973 (Box 5)
- Southern Conference Educational Fund 1973-1974 (Box 5)
- Soviet Anti-Semitism 1973 (Box 6)
- Soviet Union 1973-1974 (Box 6)
- Spartacist League 1973-1974 (Box 6)
- Spartacist League (Chicago) 1973 (Box 6)
- Stapleton, William H. 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Steel Folder 1974 (Box 6)
- Student Mobilization Committee (SMC) 1971 (Box 6)
- Student Mobilization Committee 1974 (Box 6)
- Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee 1973 (Box 6)
- Students for a Democratic Society 1973-1974 (Box 6)
- Subversive Activities—Cases related to; Updated by Library of Congress 1974 (Box 6)
- Subversive Activities Control 1972 (Box 6)
- Subversive Activities Control Act 1971-1972 (Box 6)
- Subversive Activities Control Board Documents 1973 (Box 6)
- Sutton, Anthony Hoover Institution 1973 (Box 6)
- Symbionese Liberation Party 1974 (Box 6)
- Taylor, Brad 1971 (Box 6)
- Terrorists 1973-1974 (Box 6)
- Third World Reader Service 1973 (Box 6)
- Tuler, Charles A. 1972 (Box 6)
- U 1974 (Box 6)
- Vietnamese Group Visiting Washington—Biographical Information 1972 (Box 6)
- Vouchers n.d. (Box 6)
- DeWitt White 1974 (Box 6)
- Williams, Robert 1971 (Box 6)
- Witnesses—(Future) 1973 (Box 6)
- Witness—Gentile, G. Marvin 1974 (Box 6)
- Witness—Johnson, Wayne 1971 (Box 6)
- Witness—McKay, John 1974 (Box 6)
- Witness—Niland, Frank 1974 (Box 6)
- Witness on Cuba—Phillips, Ruby Hart 1971 (Box 6)
- Witness—Rogovoy, Jay A. (Inspector) 1974 (Box 6)
- Witness—Sabin, Joseph C. (Jr.) 1974 (Box 6)
- Witness—Wu Shen-Jen 1973 (Box 6)
- Weldon, Charles (Dr.) Minority Witness 1972 (Box 6)
- Workers League 1973 (Box 6)
- Worker's Revolutionary Party 1974 (Box 6)
- Workers World Party 1971-1974 (Box 7)
- World Federalists—USA 1973-1974 (Box 7)
- Wounded Knee Legal Defense/Office Committee 1974 (Box 7)
- Young Workers Liberation League 1971-1974 (Box 7)
- Youth Against War and Fascism 1973-1974 (Box 7)
- Youth International Party 1973-1974 (Box 7)
- Young Workers Liberation League 1973 (Box 7)
- Young Socialist Alliance n.d. (Box 7)
- Yugoslavia 1973 (Box 7)
- H.R. 89 Change the Name of the Committee 1969 (Box 7)
- H.R. 132 Bolling—Establishment and Jurisdiction of Standing Committees 1973-1974 (Box 7)
- H.R. 278 Travel Restriction 1973 (Box 7)
- H.R 819 Ichord—Ashbrook and others 1971 (Box 7)
- H.R. 1169 Protection of Defense Production 1973 (Box 7)
- H.R. 1594 Ichord—Travel Restriction 1973 (Box 7)
- H.R. 1595 Protection of Defense Production 1973 (Box 7)
- H.R. 2691 Travel Restriction 1973 (Box 7)
- H.R. 3999 Travel Restriction 1973 (Box 7)
- H.R. 8023 Travel (Clean Bill) n.d. (Box 7)
- H.R. 8023 Travel Bill (Correspondence) 1973 (Box 7)
- H.R. 9669 Subversive Activities Control Board n.d. (Box 7)
- H.R. 16742 Travel Restriction—Ichord 1972 (Box 7)
- S. 177 Travel Bill—Thurmond n.d. (Box 7)
- S. 1733 Restrictions on Travel 1973 (Box 7)
- Bound Volumes: Stenographic Transcripts of Hearings Before the Committee on Internal Security, House of Representatives 1971-1974 (Box 8)
  50 volumes
- Card File Index, ca. 19,500 cards (Box 8)
  Card File Tray 76: Aar-Bez
  Card File Tray 77: Bia-Che
  Card File Tray 78: Chi-Cza
  Card File Tray 79: Dab-Eze
  Card File Tray 80: Fac-Glu
  Card File Tray 81: Gob-His
  Card File Tray 82: Hoa-Jus
  Card File Tray 83: Kad-Lev
  Card File Tray 84: Lew-Mey
  Card File Tray 85: Mia-Nyo
  Card File Tray 86: Oak-Pyl
  Card File Tray 87: Qua-Rys
  Card File Tray 88: Saa-Sny
  Card File Tray 89: Sob-Szi
  Card File Tray 90: Tab-Waz
  Card File Tray 91: Wea-Zwi